# **Kyle Sousa**

Phone: 239-770-0763 | Email: <u>KyleSousa756@gmail.com</u> | Silver Springs, FL 34488 GitHub: <u>github.com/AWSMProdigy</u> | Portfolio: <u>https://tinyurl.com/2yx7czzm</u> | LinkedIn:

https://tinyurl.com/2p82cp2h

### **Professional Summary:**

Back-end developer with college and bootcamp experience. Has a deep understanding of agile workflow and team cooperation using Git. Capable of creating complex data structures and quickly adapting to any existing back-end solution. Extensive experience creating back-end servers with the skill to implement functionality into the front-end.

## **Technical Skills**

~90 WPM, Python Django, NodeJS, ExpressJs, MongoDB, PHP, MERN, MySQL, Git, MVC, ReactJS, AngularJS, HandlebarsJS, HTML/CSS, GraphQL, RESTful API, Bootstrap, Data structures, Office 365, Linux shell, Javascript, Object-Oriented Programming

# Portfolio/Projects

**Reel Cinema:** <a href="https://github.com/AWSMProdigy/Theater-website">https://github.com/AWSMProdigy/Theater-website</a> | <a href="https://intense-lake-77911.herokuapp.com/">https://intense-lake-77911.herokuapp.com/</a>

- Theater website made for a modern age for theatergoers who enjoy watching movies with their friends but have issues planning on a time and place.
- Uses MySQL and ExpressJs to create a friends list and connect users with the reservations they and their friends have created.
- User creation with authentication

Dangerous to go Alone: <a href="https://github.com/AWSMProdigy/dangerous-to-go-alone">https://github.com/AWSMProdigy/dangerous-to-go-alone</a> | <a href="https://sheltered-taiga-89649.herokuapp.com/">https://sheltered-taiga-89649.herokuapp.com/</a>

- Website created to help gamers find others with similar interests to play games with
- Allows user to use his library, availability, and other preferences to find suitable candidates to play games with
- Is a MERN stack application, using GraphQL queries to retrieve information from the Mongo database implemented

## **Professional Experience**

Deli Clerk 2019-2020

- Fulfill customer orders while providing exemplary customer service
- Communicate with customers and handle complaints

Sales Representative 2018-2019

- Create and maintain relationships with customers
- Sell myself and my products
- Maintain precise scheduling

### Education

UCF Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp	2021
Computer Science Major, University of Florida	2018-present